Register to The Richard Donovan Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Richard Donovan Papers
1913-1971
MSS 7
Yale University Music Library
20
(30 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the American composer, conductor, and educator Richard Donovan (1891-1970)
Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Richard Donovan Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Richard Donovan, Jr. and David Donovan in 1972.
Arrangement
In 8 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Photographs. III. Programs. IV. Newspaper Clippings. V. Classroom Materials. VI. Personal Effects. VII. Donovan's Works. VIII. Works of Other Composers.
Scope and Contents
The Richard Donovan Papers contain material from Donovan's long and active life as a composer, teacher, conductor, and important musical force in the New Haven area. They include approximately 300 personal letters; correspondence concerning the publication of his works; material dealing with the American Composers Alliance and the Yaddo festivals; photographs (chiefly of Donovan); concert programs; newspaper clippings, ranging from reviews of his works to articles on 20th-century composers and book reviews; many classroom notebooks from his years as a professor at the Yale School of Music; sketches, holographs, transparencies, photocopies and published versions of his musical works; and musical works of other contemporary composers.
Donovan's works cover a wide variety of genres. In the field of vocal music he wrote several songs for solo voice, and works for chorus with orchestral accompaniment as well as many choral arrangements, anthems, and secular part-songs. He favored the oboe as a solo instrument for his chamber music, but also composed two piano trios, a quartet for woodwinds, and several works for unusual combinations such as his Soundings, for trumpet, bassoon, and percussion. His keyboard works include two suites for piano, and three pieces for organ (Antiphon and Chorale being the best known). American folk tunes figure in many of Donovan's compositions, especially in his orchestral music. New England Chronicle and Passacaglia on Vermont Folk Tunes are to be noted here. Other orchestral works include a symphony, two symphonic poems, and overtures. Several of Donovan's pieces have been recorded, and many were performed regularly during his lifetime both in America and abroad. The Papers also contain a small sampling (in holograph, photoduplicated and printed form) of works by other 20th-century composers. Everett Helm, Paul Hindemith, Horatio Parker, Quincy Porter, and Halsey Stevens number among those represented.
Within the correspondence collection are letters from such contemporary composers as Aaron Copland, Peggy Glanville-Hicks, Howard Hanson, Ernst Krenek, Otto Luening, Walter Piston, Quincy Porter, Mel Powell, Carl Ruggles, Gunther Schuller, Halsey Stevens, Randall Thompson and Virgil Thomson. A small collection of correspondence between Donovan and Beckett Gibbs, found within the classroom materials, points out Donovan's interest in the performance of plainsong. Father Gibbs specialized in that field, and Donovan wrote him numerous letters asking for detailed information.
The Donovan Papers would be of greatest interest to those doing research on musical events in New Haven and New York between 1920 and 1969; to those seeking information on the development and activities of the Yaddo festivals and the American Composers Alliance; to those following the growth and changes in the Yale School of Music; and certainly to those studying any aspect of 20th-century music.
Biographical / Historical
Richard Frank Donovan was born in New Haven, Connecticut on November 29, 1891. He attended the Yale School of Music and the Institute of Musical Art, receiving his bachelor's degree from the latter in 1922. He also taught at the Institute (later known as the Juilliard School) for several years. After teaching, conducting, and playing the organ in New York, Donovan became the director of music at the Taft School in Watertown, Connecticut in 1920. Three years later he joined the music faculty at Smith College, and in 1928 he returned to the Yale School of Music, first as an instructor, and later (1947) as Battell Professor of the Theory of Music; he also served as Acting Dean in 1940-1941.
In addition to teaching, Donovan served in several other musical capacities in New Haven. He conducted the Bach Cantata Club from 1933 until 1944, worked with the New Haven Symphony Orchestra as associate conductor from 1936 until 1951, and was organist and choirmaster of Christ Church from 1928 until 1966. Donovan was also affiliated with the Pan American Association of Composers and Yaddo (for which he served as a director of the corporation). He served on the Board of Governors of the American Composers Alliance, and was a member of the Executive Board of New Music publications.
Richard Donovan died on August 22, 1970 in Middletown, Connecticut.
Composers -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Organ music; Piano music; Symphonies -- Scores; Archer, Violet, 1913-2000; Barzin, Leon, 1900-1999; Claflin, Avery, 1898-1979; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965; Creston, Paul, 1906-1985; Crosby, John, 1926-2002; Dahl, Ingolf, 1912-1970; Damrosch, Frank, 1859-1937; Daniel, Oliver; Davison, Archibald T. (Archibald Thompson), 1883-1961; Dethier, Gaston M. (Gaston Marie), 1875-1958; Diemer, Emma Lou, 1927-; Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970; Etler, Alvin, 1913-1973; Forsyth, Cecil, 1870-1941; Frankenstein, Alfred V. (Alfred Victor), 1906-1981; Freed, Isadore, 1900-1960; Glanville-Hicks, Peggy, 1912-1990; Goetschius, Percy, 1853-1943; Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981; Heath, Fenno, 1926-2008; Hillis, Margaret, 1921-1998; Hughes, Anselm, 1889-1974; Jones, Charles, 1910-1997; Kay, Ulysses, 1917-1995; Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991; Krenz, Jan, 1926-; Krigbaum, Charles; Lewin, Frank; List, Eugene, 1918-1985; Luening, Otto, 1900-1996; Mannes, Leopold, 1899-1964; Mattfeld, Victor H. (Victor Henry), 1917-2007; Moore, Douglas, 1893-1969; Noss, Luther, 1907-1995; Piston, Walter, 1894-1976; Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966; Powell, Mel, 1923-1998; Read, Gardner, 1913-2005; Ruggles, Carl, 1876-1971; Schuller, Gunther, 1925-2015; Schuman, William, 1910-1992; Sessions, Roger, 1896-1985; Sheridan, Frank, 1898-1962; Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949; Stevens, Halsey, 1908-1989; Stone, Kurt; Thompson, Randall, 1899-1984; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Wilson, Keith L. (Keith Leroy), 1916-2013; Wyner, Yehudi, 1929-; American Composers Alliance; Yaddo (Artists' colony)
- Correspondence, 1913-1970; Series I; 4 Boxes
  General
  Correspondence is organized in the following categories:
  A. Letters to Richard Donovan, arranged in alphabetical order by the last name of the sender. Within each name, the letters are then placed in chronological order. Unidentified material is grouped together at the end of the alphabet, followed by miscellaneous letters from and to people other than Donovan.
  B. Letters.from Donovan, arranged in alphabetical order by the last name of recipient. Again, within each name the letters are organized chronologically. Recommendations and unidentified letters are filed at the end.
  C. Concerning publication: subdivided into 3 categories--legal, letters between Donovan and the various publishing houses, and miscellaneous correspondence. Within these categories the letters are arranged alphabetically and/or chronologically.
  The final divisions (D E F G) concern American Composers Alliance, Yaddo festivals, and the Yale School of Music, and the New Haven Symphony Orchestra respectively.
  - Correspondence - To Donovan, I.A
    - Aldridge, Harry G., Jr., 1962 Dec. 19; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Archer, Violet, 1950-1956; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Archer, Violet, no date; card. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ausubel, David, 1945 Jan. 4; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Banks, Dick, 1954 Nov. 8; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barzin, Leon, 1942 Jan. 15; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Beale, Jim, 1957 Sep. 25; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Beale, Jim, 1957 Dec. 19; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Beale, Jim, 1958 Oct. 16; postcard. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Berman, Harry, 1954 Jun. 27; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Brooks, Allerton F., 1938 Dec. 6; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Browne, Richmond, 1967 Jan. 8; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Christ-Janer, Albert, 1955-1957; 8 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Claflin, Avery, 1968 Apr. 5; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Collins, V. Lansing, 1933 Jul. 3; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cooke, John D., 1947 Nov. 6; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Copland, Aaron, 1932-1952; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cowell, Henry, 1954 Oct. 17; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cowell, Sidney, 1965 May 9; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Creston, Paul, 1958 Aug. 22; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Creston, Paul, 1958 Sep. 28; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Crosby, John O., 1967 Oct. 27; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Curtis, Tane, autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dahl, Ingolf, 1959 Apr. 28; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      (added 1982 Jul.)
    - Dalton, James, 1957-1966; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Damrosch, Frank, 1919 Oct. 28; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Daniel, Oliver, 1967 Nov. 29; telegram. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Davison, Archibald, 1927 Mar. 14; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dethier, Gaston M., no date; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Diemer, Emma Lou, 1959 May 21; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Diemer, Emma Lou, 1965 Dec.; card. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Donovan, Fr. Vincent C.O.P., 1930 Oct. 13; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Donovan, Fr. Vincent C.O.P., 1942 Sep. 13; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Douglas, Winfred, 1930 Dec. 2; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Downey, Fairfax, 1929 Dec. 20; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Edwards, Deane, 1956; 2 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Edsall, Laurence, no date; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Etler, Alvin, 195D Aug. 29; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Everitt, Alice L., 1962 Dec. 5; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Flanders, Helen Hartness, 1950 Jan. 18; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Forsyth, Cecil, 1921-1934; 4 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Frankenstein, Alfred, 1956 May 21; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Freed, Isadore, 1956 Jan. 16; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Garland, ? and ?, no date; card. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Geffen, Felicia, 1963 Feb. 4; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Gladwell, H.V., 1953 Oct. 16; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Glanville-Hicks, Peggy, no date; 2 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Goetschius, "Papa", 1927; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Golz, Effie and Walter, 1956 Jan. 19; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Gratz, John, 1952 Mar. 23; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hanson, Howard, 1954 Nov. 10; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Heath, Fenno, no date; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hudson, William L., 1967 Aug. 9; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hughes, Rev. Dom Anselm OSB, 1929 Aug. 3; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hulen, G.L., no date; memo. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jacobson, George H., 1957 Dec. 6; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jenkins, Paul, 1962 Apr. 13; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jenkins, Ruth, 1955 Nov. 10; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Johnson, Edgar, 1956 Jan. 6; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Johns, Cornelius, 1953 Nov. 23; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jones, Charles, 1952 Jan. 9; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kates, David, 1953-1954; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kaufmann, Henry, 1956 Apr. 23; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kay, Ulysses, 1967; 2 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kendrick, Harold, 1953 Nov. 24; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kerr, Marian J., no date; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kibitz, Bill, 1966 May 22; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kincaid, William M., 1954-1957; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - King, J.R., 1954 Apr. 26; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1938 Dec. 7; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Kohon, Harold, 1957 May 23; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Krenek, Ernst, 1942 Jun. 2; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Krenz, Jan, 1965 Apr. 27; telegram. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Krigbaum, Virginia Lee and Charles, no date; card. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Krimm, Gerald G., 1965 May 3; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lee, Daggett, 1963 Jul. 3; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Leek, Eleanor, 1961-1962; 7 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Leek, Eleanor, 1967 Feb. 21; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lewin, Frank, 1955-1967; 5 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lewin, Frank and Elsbeth, 1958 Jan. 6; card. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lewis, Merrills, 1960 Mar. 21; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - List, Eugene, 1954 Apr. 12; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Loudis, Anthony J., 1953; 3 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Luening, Otto, 1953 Nov. 28; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mahaffy, Bob, 1966; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mallet, Fr. Jean, 1962 Mar. 21; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mannes, Leopold, 1962 Aug. 8; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mattfeld, Victor, 1959; no date; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Matthays, Jessie, no date Jul. 31; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - McKinney, Howard D., 1939 Dec. 3; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Moore, Douglas, 1947-1963; no date; 3 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Nakaseko, Kayn, 1956 Aug. 15; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Veilson, W.H., 1923 Apr. 23; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Nissen, Arthur E., 1956 Jan. 23; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Noss, Luther, 1954 Nov. 9; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - O'Meara, Eva J., no date; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Page, Cleveland A., 1960 Sep. 12; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Pitta, Mercedes, 1954 Oct. 21; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Piston, Walter, 1936-1951; 3 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Piston, Walter, no date; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Porter, Quincy, 1946 Apr. 3; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Powell, Mel, 1957 Jul. 25; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Powell, Mel, 1958 Jan. 2; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Read, Gardner, 1959 May 1; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Reed, Elizabeth, no date; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Reinwald, Karl, 1967 Jan. 30; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Richey, David, 1962-1967; 3 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Rogers, Meyric R., 1957 Dec. 5; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Riegger, Wallingford, no date; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Analysis & score to String Qt. no. 1
    - Ruggles, Carl, 1934; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Schuller, Gunther A., 1965; 3 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Schuman, Bill, 1952 Apr. 4; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Sessions, Roger, 1934 Jan. 31; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Shakford, David, 1954 Aug. 10; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Skelton, Bill, 1961-1963; 4 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Smith, David Stanley, 1926-1928; 6 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Smith, E.W., 1953 Nov. 20; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Speelman, Leslie P., 1956; 3 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Stevens, Halsey, 1960-1966; 3 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Stone, Kurt, 1965 Mar. 19; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Suderburg, Robert, 1967 Aug. 27; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Taplin, Frank E., 1954 Feb. 2; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Temerson, Leon, 1953 Jul. 9; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Thatcher, Robert S., 1960 Mar. 18; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Thompson, Randall, 1951 Oct. 24; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1951-1952; 2 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Timm, Everett, 1967 Oct. 30; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Twyefort, Barbara, 1952 Oct. 17; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Watkins, Morris, 1934; 2 typed letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Weed, J. Laiten, 1968 Feb. 7; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1929 Jun. 19; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wilson, Keith, 1962 Aug. 16; typed letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wyner, Yehudi, 1962-1966; 2 autograph letters signed. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Unidentifiable, 7 postcards. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Unidentifiable, card. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Unidentifiable, 4 autograph letters. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Unidentifiable, 5 typed letters. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - From W. H. H. to William Neilson, 1923 Apr. 10; typed letter signed (carbon).
      - From Whiteford, Joseph to Rev. W. G. Kibitz, 1954 Mar. 2; typed letter (carbon).
      - From Porter, Quincy to Edgar S. Furniss, 1940 Mar. 27; typed letter (carbon).
      - From Porter, Quincy to Edwin M. Borchard, 1940 Mar. 28; typed letter signed.
  - Correspondence - From Donovan, I.B
    - Beaux Arts Trio, 1963 Oct. 8; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Daniel, Oliver, 1954 Mar. 3; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Frankenstein, Alfred, no year Apr. 16; autograph letter. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Glanville-Hicks, Peggy, 1956 Jan. 29; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hillis, Margaret, 1956 Dec. 7; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hutchinson, G.E., 1958 Jan. 30, no date; 2 cards. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Added 1982 Jul.
      Each card contains a round by Donovan in his hand.
    - Killough, Richard, no date; autograph letter. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Killough, Richard, 1966 Feb, 8; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Kohon, Harold, 1957 May 20; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Korn, Richard, 1956 Sep. 26; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Leek, Eleanor, 1962 Jan. 25; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mannes, Leopold, 1962 Nov. 3; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Martone, Elizabeth, 1967 Jan. 21; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Nissen, Arthur, 1960 Sep. 13; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Page, Cleveland A., 1960 Sep. 10; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Reed, Elizabeth, 1962 Apr. 17; typed letter signed (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Ribbelink, Jo, 1964 Nov. 16; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Sass, Mrs., 1963; autograph letter signed. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Schuller, Gunther, 1965 May 19; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Skelton, Bill, 1963 Feb. 8; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Spelman, Leslie, 1956 Mar. 21; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Stone, Kurt, 1965 Apr. 1; typed letter (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Whetten, Nathan Laselle, 1959 Jan. 10; autograph letter. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Recommendations, 1959-1967; 2 autographs. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified, 1963; 2 typed letters (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence Concerning Publication, I.C
    Letters to and from Donovan, contracts, miscellaneous.
    - Requests and permissions for texts (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - From Donovan, 10 typed letters (carbon), 1 autograph letter.
      - To Donovan, 10 typed letters signed, 2 autograph letters signed, postcard.
    - Copyright material (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - From Donovan, 1940-1966; 3 typed letters (carbon).
      - To Donovan, 1956-1962; 3 typed letters signed.
    - Registration certificates, 1950-1961; 5 certificates. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Arrow Music Press, 1939-1956; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Associated Music Publishers, 1952-1956; 13 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Augsburg Publishing House, 1959; 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Boosey & Hawkes, 1943-1970; 19 items. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1945-1957; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Broude Brothers (& Alexander Broude), 1954-1956; 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - J. Fischer & Bros., 1941-1962; 9 items. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Free Library of Philadelphia, 1944-1962; 9 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - H.W. Gray, 1948-1957; 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mercury Music, 1950-1959; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - C.F. Peters, 1962-1964; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Theodore Presser, 1956-1962; 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Publishers, 19 items. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      A-R Editions [3]; Silver Burdett [21]; Concordia Publishing House [1]; Carl Fischer [2]; Galaxy Music Corp. [3]; E.F. Kalmus [2]; Edward B. Marks Music Corp. [1]; Merion Music [1]; Mills Music [1]; Music Press [3].
    - Miscellaneous Publishers, 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      National Broadcasting Co. [2]; New Music Edition [2]; E.C. Schirmer [1]; Stainer & Bell [3]; Summy Publishing [4]; Alec Templeton [1]; Valley Music Press [1].
    - Other, 13 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Concerning reproduction, etc.
    - Recording Companies, 19 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Columbia Records [9]; Contemporary Records [2]; Mary Howard Recordings [1]; Mercury Record Corp. [1]; New Music Recordings [2]; RCA Victor [2]; Vanguard Recording Society [2].
  - ACA papers, I.D
    - Works deposited in ACA Library
      Letters concerning and releases for same.
      - 1950-1955, 30 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1956-1959, 20 items. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1960-1971, 24 items. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Donovan as member and/or president
      - General letters to members, 1952-1963; 18 items. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Agendas, minutes, Articles of Association, etc., 1950-1957; 14 items. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Laurel Leaf Award citations (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Yaddo papers, I.E
    - From Elizabeth Ames to Donovan, 1933-1968; 20 typed letters signed. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - From Donovan to Elizabeth Ames, no date; 2 autograph letters (1 signed). (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - From Polly ? to Donovan, 1967-1968; 6 typed letters signed. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - From E. Ames to Quincy Porter, 1954 Sep. 21; 1 typed letters (carbon). (Box 4, Folder 2)